all right good mornin I went back and
we're you watched or died didn't we
watch the whole thing where we watched
the last part to write down our goals to
know whether or not we we've done them
or not I didn't rewatch the part where
we talked about the structure I'm
guessing I think it was like we
introduced who we are what goals we said
we were gonna do whether we did them or
not if we didn't I guess why we didn't
and if we did how we felt about it what
we learned what happens I don't know if
we wanted to play with it whether we
want to do all of that at once or
interrupt one another which were pretty
good at in our families I don't know
what you're talking about
it's doing it not with other members of
our family that is true it plays out
well in the family like I'm there's no I
don't think there's necessarily an issue
um do you want to go first you want me
to go universe all right so my name is
Jubilee I don't have my elevator pitch
that's what we were talking about on
Friday creating the global tech
cooperative to give us all the tools we
need to solve our problems from the
individual to the global dealing with
personal autonomy group autonomy and
global efficiency and allowing anyone to
come and contribute in a way that works
for them and ask for help in a way that
works for them so that's that's big here
I'm here to work on the idea cafe
YouTube channel to figure out what it
takes to have a meaningful conversation
with other humans and humanity as a
whole so big things all around last week
I said I would post a facebook a
specifically this parenting group about
creating an idea cafe which I did and I
love when I do that because it never
comes to anything but other things
happen other things around it happen and
that is exactly what happened but it
feels like in that group I'm sure
they're just like oh I think no it
and no one does no one knows kind of
pick it up and run with it but other
things always happen around it it's like
the universe tells me to do something I
do it and then magic happens in other
ways which is why I keep listening to it
I also said I would pick three topics I
kind of picked them live last week and
then also like I said it would be
overwhelming if all of them delivered
themselves and one delivered itself in a
pretty strong way I hosted four
different idea cafes this last week on
communism and Marxism in the game be
space and learnt a lot about what it
means to have an idea cafe and
understood now I'm gonna put out two to
the game be people a Bentley did a
Google poll he's the one who I'm crazy
and the other tech both on Fridays
asking when most game people game be
people are available we're gonna pick
one time slot that works weekly and have
a ongoing discussion showcase what that
conversation looks like and if it
doesn't work on the YouTube channel we
will go to zoom so that there's there's
more people to be able to have a
conversation with so that is what
happened following and then my I also
mentioned that I have my own personal
goals which are for the next 60 days
until the new year to not smoke pot do
yoga daily meditate daily keep my house
clean I have a few other things that are
kind of in there like clean one room a
day cleaning one room in a wasn't
official and it hasn't happened as much
as the other ones I've definitely
meditated every day
Donnie obey even if it was a couple
stretches every day and although I
totally and now and then I haven't
smoked pot for a week and a half the
cravings are coming back like wait this
is a long time that you went without it
I'm allowing myself this weekend last
weekend as well to smoked CBD like so
smoking pot but on THC so I just already
smoked at this party and I'm like cuz
I'm sure I went am at 9 a.m. in the
morning allowed myself to smoke THC but
I was like go for it do it all you want
I don't care you're not high it's not
gonna do anything just leaves the gross
taste that's what you get you're welcome
you're welcome so that is I believe
where I am this week and I'm sure we'll
talk more about what challenges
we have and moving forward but I'll let
you introduce yourself and your goals
and what you did this last week already
thank you alright so my name is Adriel I
am working on a project to fight
misinformation it's called wiki election
and to start with it's focusing on
fighting misinformation and politics and
science and then it will expand out from
there so my goal last week was to create
some content to better explain where the
things are at are very like I guess what
the plans are for the part of it that
will discuss scientific studies and
articles in that type of thing because I
think as we talked about last week one
of the next steps seems like it should
be going to go to places like UBC
actually talking to some science you
know some ta some professors whoever
will listen and just see if we can get
some people who are interested in might
want help answer some questions now to
sort of plan out and then also people
who are interested in the long run to
actually do some of these article
reviews and that type of thing actually
did quite good
I got spent more than these three hours
that I wanted to and got I think three
or four pretty good pieces of content
they don't look all that nice but that
wasn't the goal anyway and that did
uncover now that I'm getting deeper and
it's starting to get more complex to
explain starting to wonder if it makes
sense to explain it all sort of under
one umbrella or if it makes sense to
split them for now to sort of have like
one thing that's focusing on politics
and elections and and that type of thing
and then one channel that focus is on
the scientific discussion part of it
that will end up branching out into
things like economics and legislation
but sort of experts or at least the
skilled discussing complex topics
that's where our that something like
you're done which doesn't happen in our
family just keep talking to the other
person I could I know no because that's
also a piece of it is remembering to
stop talking other people can start who
are comfortable instructing oh that's
the thing mm-hmm
interesting interesting real-world you
probably work on interrupting more no
why do we have to change they should
learn how to jump in jump in
mid-sentence that's what it finish the
thought for them and continue on this is
how we play off each other well we'll
have to figure that out if a third
person joins us yeah how was your week
been how was it to sit down and do it I
did it was it like all one big go for
three hours plus I can't usually do that
and almost anything it's it's usually
like two different half-hour sort of you
know throwing spaghetti at the wall and
trying to see like what makes sense and
thinking through it and then once I
actually got going I already know spent
an hour once where I sort of started to
make some stuff and then the next night
I spent like I don't know two hours
maybe three hours and then they I had
like the best sleep I've had in weeks
like but is there anything you want to
work on like I mean not just the
goal-setting but that I can help let you
just brainstorming how some part of it
is that the idea of does it make sense
to split this into different and I'm
calling it brands cuz you know it's the
way to sort of put a face to I'm gonna
organization is the right word but
better ones not and not to come into
mind the end goal is they'll end up
being a part of the same thing it's sort
of two sides of the same coin where the
politics side is really more about like
creating a background for people in the
you know years down the road it'll
likely be more than just politicians
it'll be people who claim to be experts
it's gonna be scientists journalists
people who you want to see like what is
this person doing over the long run what
kind of stuff are they doing who who's
paying them where does their money come
from
you know does the community find they
lean one way or the other that kind of
thing so that it's not to say if they're
that bad or that we filter it out but
it's that any work that person does you
have you have some context to previous
report that that person has done things
things they've been right or wrong about
that kind of thing and on the content
side it's all about well sort of
understanding complex topics like
science economics
legislation getting feedback from
variety of sources see where they agree
and disagree and then ideally boiling
that up
summarizing it at sort of a higher level
so you can see if there's ten studies on
the same topic what do they agree on
what do they not agree on you know are
the ones that all agree and disagree it
is one of those groups have particularly
bad you know where their experiments not
designed properly if you have sketchy
funding it's to stuff like that so they
start out sounding fairly different and
I think that to start with people who
are interested in wanting to contribute
would be different people in some cases
they might be the same but largely
you're having people who are super
interested in politics and making sure
people have useful information during
elections now on the other side is just
trying to sort of help solve did deus
information in in to start with in
science by actually getting into the
weeds and reviewing individual studies
ya know and for both them like for the
politicians in particular you want to be
able to have like the IBD the background
of the politician and same with in
science like what is a scientist done
who funds them where what universe do
they go to what's their background and
then there's also that another another
layer of like the crowd that's
participating whether they have a degree
or not is a piece of information but
it's not as important as do they get it
right do they do they understand the
stuff beyond what are they in the box of
being able to have a degree from
seizures yeah
I think in the early stages we just
focus on like public experts and then
the community can vote but the end goal
is to let anybody contribute and then it
becomes all about okay but are they
right yeah you have to have a PhD or not
if they get ninety five percent of their
predictions and things they did they say
end up you know everyone either true
awesome yeah
yeah no those are important and so also
you just talked about branding and split
it apart I think the other thing also is
even naming it right it's called wiki
elections which definitely goes to
politics and then figuring out what how
to empower that right how to empower the
voter for the politician including an
angel with the election as well as a
kind of name that for two purposes one
is that it's a wiki on election so on
politics but but there's also a wiki
powered by elections because people are
voting on you know what's true and
what's not and it was like they're
they're submitting information and the
whole idea is that one particularly
well-spoken person can't take over the
conversation because they're in heavy
conversations with words they're having
it with data or I guess through data the
you can read things people can vote on
if a certain thing is true or not and
then when that happens enough at the
lower level you start to learn things at
the higher levels and people are are
submitting news articles and how a
certain politician and voted that they
can vote on so for example how a
politician voted you would vote on what
that legislation means is that you know
pro-environment is it pro-business is it
Pro it you know where they just rights
that kind of thing and then if people
vote for or against it you can start to
see the the way they lean you can start
to see what they value and that's not
trying to say right or wrong it's just
saying here's the values that the
community seems to think that the this
person has mhm you know there's so many
different iterations that it can take
this thing we've had this conversation
before I know I've had it with other
people of like creating a fantasy
politics game so that like feeds into
the system where like you pick your
politician you see are they gonna and
it's just as simple as do they vote with
their constituents right you know and so
therefore you have to pull
all constituents and then they just vote
and you either get one so they don't get
points but unlike fantasy football and
hockey and everything else it actually
affects the game right like I chose how
much I don't play sports Gretzky is
gonna play hockey better how do we have
played it like thirty years they
wouldn't play hockey better because
people have him on his 13 but I but
politicians can and should vote better
based on oh I have to vote with my
constituents to get more points right it
wouldn't happen if there's a hundred
people playing but if there were a
million people played it became the new
Pokemon go and you create in a way that
it's fun interesting then you have the
crowd to kind of feed into the system
you need to create it first and get will
sell it like it's hard yeah exactly get
bigger it it gets more clout the other
part of that that's sort of an easier
step is people tend to get elected on
what they promised and that's clearly
cutting dry words here's the things that
they promised it's also keeping a track
record of that everybody that one okay
how far along are they how much have
they actually moved towards that what
have they done sometimes they push hard
and trying to deliver it they actually
do a pretty good job sometimes they push
hard to deliver their promises and
they're stonewalled and sometimes they
just get elected on a promise and then
it doesn't seem to guide their actual
policy and office at all
yeah and it's you know being able to see
that the next time around so that it
says okay well this person's platform is
good but I can see in the past they only
don't deliver on 12% of their promises
maybe actually take it with a grain of
salt
yeah obviously this is not quite related
but we went to to the local mall here on
Tuesday and it's it's a very high-end
mall with a lot of high-end stores in it
it also has been here since the late
eighties early nineties so it's okay
just they're updating it and so they
have in that in they have like a little
section it used to be sellers they found
turned into a showroom and it's actually
really nice I'm like yes I want this to
be in my neighborhood in eight years a
cool Park with a big slide that you like
can slide down and they have these giant
this giant round swing that I'm like can
we are those gonna actually be there
because I want them to be there but
they're going through the cohousing
getting it through the city I know that
like
and this was we promised it to ourselves
we wanted it the city was like no you're
not gonna want that you're not going to
want to be close to your neighbors
you're not gonna want those trees but
you have to have these trees so there's
a part that's like the bureaucracy of
the city that stops you and then there's
the piece of oh you were never actually
going to do that anyway and for this
bigger texture project but it's just to
say you have this like they're making
the second biggest library in Vancouver
they'll have to fulfill that there's no
way they're going to be able to not
fulfill that to get that through the
city but that Park might change right
the that it's on a rooftop that only
certain people can access and they
actually have amazing rooftop gardens
are they gonna make them accessible are
they gonna make it that you have to you
know I don't buy something them all to
get out there or those kind of things
it's very easy to be like oh we didn't
have the funding for that so we couldn't
do it wait you're a for-profit mall if
you're saying that you're gonna fund
those things that's part of it that's
part of using this face and yeah and
getting to stop traffic for those years
well it builds and I don't know if
they're using more space but that same
kind of thing right it's an architecture
project they're not even but to say this
is what it's gonna be and then get it
through the system versus what is it
actually gonna look like at the end and
if we had a similar project what you're
doing for all of the times that has
happened in the past we can see your
construction company actually doesn't
deliver yours doesn't seem that pros yes
and so now if you do that a couple of
times it starts to be even just during
the proposal phase you're like okay
great deck we know you're liars go away
this other company has half the you know
their proposals have is good but they
deliver so I'd rather have 100% of what
they actually say we're gonna do then 1%
of what you say you're gonna do so
absolutely not it's a big piece of like
what I sit with in my own personal
development if I like some people are
over estimators and some people are
under estimators and I don't even think
it's about lying or not lying but our
society props up the people who
overestimate and like oh I have a
trovato
and downplays the other one we should do
the opposite right if somebody is
constantly able to come off is really
amazing but they don't deliver on
anything I'd rather have the person that
like is going to over deliver on what
they promised right well I'll probably
get a mess up but I'll get a tea
that awesome I want that person who can
own it yet that person's the opposite
what it seems like they're sort of you
know that the personal goals and values
are because then it seems like okay if
this person did delivers on spending 5%
of the things they promised great which
75% is it the one cost of the least
money is it the ones that maybe benefit
the corporations the most like there's
times where there will be that overlap
but they didn't say okay these types of
promises based on your track record we
can tell you're probably not going to
deliver it goal is then just make a
bunch of tiny promises like well I
delivered you know on each of these by
one pebble goals so I pebbles I'm 99%
yeah but the big bill that actually
mattered you didn't do anything towards
so yeah and with like what are people
actually voting on because you have all
of that data that's where just the eyes
on the project just the eyes involved in
it changes it right where it's like okay
whoa we can see your track record we can
tell you I as an individual as a person
who votes can tell you which thing I
voted on to have to vote for Justin
Trudeau it wasn't on him legalizing pot
great that he did it but that wasn't it
it was an electoral reform it was all it
was First Nations regularly like all of
it he didn't flicker on anything would
yeah but you know not to get reelected
again after that that's the way the
winds were blowing anyway so it's not
like that's terribly a society governed
by marketing and that's exactly it is
it's very easy you can just promise it
you can just say it and then never
deliver on it in marketing and
advertising and all of it and so the
more were able to back that up with
actual data we can use in my world I'd
like that to be co-owned and transparent
but even if it's not just how do we
trust it and how do we get that like a
for-profit company can absolutely make
this wiki elections that you're making
you're making it under under that that
guideline as long as it's transparent
about right but what are going to get
the voting information that's publicly
available you're just using it in a way
of what you're getting from the people
is more trustworthy the more we own it
together and the more we run it together
and I think that's the future vision of
if it's better under under public
ownership is wrong because that's like
the government operative ownership
improves it at that point yeah projects
look behind the marketing and the
politics and that is people I mean in a
way they have short attention spans but
that's you know people have lives they
hear something like yeah that sounds
good I'll vote for the information
available and then they move on with
their lives I don't even now I don't
remember all the promises people made in
this past election and it was what a
month ago yeah so that two weeks ago
maybe
I voted because I yeah I like to vote on
the day of just because I feel like I'm
part of something it's the closest I get
to a sporting event I wish I could care
about these sports as much as you people
do it looks really fun I don't I know I
can't believe it's been this it'll be
ten years since thank you for happy
Olympics like I'm never walking around
the city you be like I wish why are you
but also can you care about anything
else this just a fraction of this much
just a fraction and to be able to bring
those together to be able to tap into
why do people care about sports and how
do you make it fun and interesting and
engaging to care about politics because
they also well they're promising these
platforms also kind of almost make it
boring and and the data yeah arduous
right so I do wonder how much sports
would die out if they had like you know
if ESPN and I'm forgetting a Sports
Center those different things I'm gonna
assume there but if they if they
reported wildly different on games well
you know they're like hey the Lakers
played the Spurs at one says the Lakers
101 says it's personal and they show
different highlights and I think after a
while people be like this is stupid
I don't know what actually happened I
think that's out yeah exactly
I think that's part of the issue with
politics is it's really hard to follow
it's hard to like most people know
they're probably not getting the full
truth no matter what source they go to
that gets frustrating and people even
the people that are interested end up
losing interest because they don't know
what the next step is and like they know
that they're kind of rolling dice either
way so if you actually had a shared news
source that was time crowd-sourced
yeah which is great I mean having a tool
that actually says are you telling the
truth what is what is it what is your
background in real time well it's odd
like an add-on on Chrome while you're
watching yet on ESPN but the political
ones is important and something that
honestly although they're they're
getting on Facebook to create that I'm
not going to trust into Facebook great
so we need to create it needs to be
something that we can transparently see
and put on and so we're a sourcing it
right the people in it if we're just
trusting that that person talking is
telling the truth people won't trust it
like words on YouTube on Facebook
whether they're zooming it themselves
whether it's on CNN if they just let
people you know vomit words and just
like well I'm doing my job by
broadcasting this and my job is done
yeah why why I listen to this why not
just broadcast a white wall and it like
we have eroded the trust of the public
in advertising in politics and economics
and law in cardial and everything I've
eroded it so now it's like you have to
kind of up your game and Trust just to
break even and yet like nobody trusts it
which is my issue with like crypto
currencies people like look at it it's
awesome I'm like yes it might be it
might be our solution to everything but
we already don't understand the currency
we're using and don't trust it it has to
be more understandable and more
trustworthy than what we have in order
to overtake it I think the same can be
said for all of these technology and
apps is currency exchange here in
Vancouver that nickel is a store of
something a code like 70 million dollars
you could cook every currency and then
it's like sorry guys have walked away ya
know and the more that those things
happen the less you're gonna trust you
know like even this isn't quite for
trust trust but like if you have you
because there have been future political
ops right and the more they come into
existence then go out people are like
all participating for years we are
successful right
instead of like right but if we can
bring people on and it's already
cessful like so it hurts itself and then
you're like well I'm not gonna touch it
if Google creates one but it's the only
way it's gonna be successful we're
breaking it ourselves before we find it
and so we have to be able to bring
people on board find the trust and say
well what would get you to trust it
right how can you trust me how can you
trust the system and build that into it
I think this is a big piece of that
doing it openly and honestly where you
know they mean like they can see you and
see her a real person who has and your
real goals and it comes at a cost
right people make fun of you who people
can like remind you wrong one of the
things that I think I can't escape which
of not terribly looking forward to but
you know that's the world that I'm
trying to create is I'm gonna have to
have my own page on wiki election
everything that I say goes through the
same scrutiny as every minute what else
so when certain you know when things
come out people say it's unfair like
well I have my page on there too so my
husband is a nice no saying some
relevant things after his last thing
citizen should be able to select service
has access to that data but no own it in
their servers I agree but that's never
gonna happen in our Google or if it does
it's gonna take a lot of years but and
we can create that we can create our
version of Google that actually does
that which is our Nestor knows were
there any kind of you one of the
challenges that I think all face with
this project is security at like is one
of the the tenants of it which does
restrict transparency in certain areas
and it's finding that balance between
being transparent but then also not
being overly transparent where it
becomes a security risk because I think
it's obvious that if this is successful
it's going to be the target of a lot of
influences yeah well your instance
people trying to spend money on it
people trying to hack it people trying
to just you know hire attend s of people
to come in there and add garbage data
there's a bunch of things that people
will do to try and stop it because it's
if it's it's successful a lot of people
are going to hate it it's you know
absolutely that a lot of people is going
to be less than 1% of people that's
still a lot of people and a lot of
powerful people with money and resources
so it's so I think like transparent
see we have to own that security is an
issue for sure transparency fixes a lot
of it like Wikipedia has those exact
same problems but they're not they're
not collectively owned and they can't
really crowdsource
the solution to the problem right all
they can do is kind of lock it and come
up with other solutions and you're like
this is what we're doing to the best of
our ability the more were able to
crowdsource like right there's 2,000
people that all came on and started
voting the opposite way what are we
doing about this how do we kind of let
like maybe freeze of those 2,000 well we
discuss how to how to fix that right and
maybe that's not if as long as that's
done transparently it might not be
perfect but it's better than allowing
Coke to come on and or do it for
politics but probably they get involved
in politics anyway like how do you how
do you deal with that but there's also
the internet security piece of having
the code available and having those
things and I get why for your project
that might not be doable for me it's
transparency is default not just
transparency for transparency because
transparency is the best all right I
agree with that and I would want to make
like as much of the source code
available and the underlying data but
with you know going through that layer
of like sort of the the security for
multiple angles because I don't
necessarily trust open source projects
like the results they create I do like
the fact that like if you're really into
code you can go look at the code and see
exactly what it's doing and see if it's
you know if it's weird if there's
sketchy stuff in there and that kind of
thing which because it's open there
tends not to be because anybody can open
it up and and take a look yeah and so
it's trying to find that balance yeah
absolutely and I think the a tech
cooperative in a way gets that balance
because it's if it's just open source
you might have both kind of shitty
projects like Munsell as much as I like
it the Mozilla people use Chrome when
they're doing their work that says
something that says something huge and
so we can have the best of both worlds
but just aren't like honoring just that
hey bugzilla employees why are using
chrome how do we prove it until it's at
the state right where they're at least
even is if they're even in their in
their speed I'm using Mozilla but
knowing that they they and this was from
five years ago maybe they no longer you
problem I don't know but has Mozilla
improved chrome house and so owning that
for-profit companies have an advantage
in the improvement and innovation force
doesn't mean but they're also hurting
our environment or social structure I do
think we can have the best of both
worlds by just owning that by saying how
do we improve it right if it's if
Mozilla shittier than chrome how do we
improve it yeah without just like use it
because it's better use it because it's
socially just use it no is it better
chrome is interesting because there's
Chrome which is the front end the world
used to but then as chromium which is
kind of like the platform that chrome is
based on that now Opera is based on
Internet Explorer is is based on who's
going to be based on about a hundred
percent clear on that but it it's Google
is a weird company where where comes to
that because they're obviously
profit-seeking and they have some stuff
in their you know in their history that
you're like why why did you do that and
like you know then working with the
military and their employees not being
very happy with that
but then they also and I'm not sure that
you can learn my from this because I've
seen any one of the only for-profit
companies it actually is that a good
internet citizen yes like they have full
teams of security researchers I don't
think they monetize this in any way that
Doyle and look for vulnerabilities and
sort of alert the public to you might be
an issue in chrome it might be in with
you know iPhones they just look for
security flaws yeah which i think is
important and important if they're doing
good work propping them up for that
helping them find more people to do that
and move if and when they're doing evil
work also know bad Google don't work
with the Chinese government to surveil
their citizens go bad
that's kind of going back to the wiki
election part where it's you know the
history on people part of that's also
tracking board members and okay you were
a part of this board that made this
decision the public really isn't happy
about that we're gonna follow you and
every board you ever go on yeah so that
we can either you know heads up that
this person is on that board so watch
out for the company or just if they're
bad enough completely boycott that
company until that person's not on the
dpor anymore and then also on the other
side I guess kind of on the same side
that on the politics part we're gonna
have to track the political parties
because while I'm not always a fan of
how parties work and held daily out
there not going anywhere
and they indisputably like they sway
even people who don't necessarily buy
under the full part party platform once
they're in office is surrounded by by
people that party they usually kind of
told the party line and a lot of times
you you you can't even be the leader
unless you're like fully in on all of
them which is the irony of like if
you're a liberal representation in
Canada you have to vote with the
Liberals but you're still voting as an
individual it's like wait really like
why not just vote as a bloc you're gonna
vote as a bloc yes
where is reading the technology to track
them makes it so they might not vote as
a bloc you know what I'd rather be
independent and work with my
constituents then look under you even be
funnier but so on that same side they
way that we'll be tracking a political
party sort of the history of that seeing
how they trend but then also how the
members of that party so you know
they're the ones actually contributing
to the data for a tea party do the same
thing for corporations here's the D
decision this corporation made here's
who was on the board here's you know who
was involved in that decision so that
we're we're tracking the lowest highest
exactly you know so that you can track
the public personas involved in that and
sort of the organization as a whole and
how they interact you might be you know
a part of a board that made a decision
that people didn't like okay he voted
against it so actually that person is
good yeah just because you were a part
and to go teach tear point hopefully in
politics that would have them vote how
they actually feel they should and you
know how their constituents feel that
they should instead of well this is how
the party is voting so if I want to be a
part of the next vote I have to vote to
put them absolutely and so that's a big
piece of like it feeding back into the
system if it's changing the system it's
looking at and same a science right oh
wait they can tear this apart we better
make it even extra strong and so if they
can't go back and do that to old ones
but they can definitely do that for
future ones
so we're at the 33 minute mark or
supposed to keep these kind of sort of
to half an hour's so that people one
might watch them it doesn't we know we
can talk about this technology and
information and politics for hours on
so we can wrap this up with what you
want to commit to in the next week and
then say goodbye to YouTube all right um
I've torn between two things one is to
update the prototype for the the
election part the sort of you know pick
the top three popular candidates in the
Democratic race in the US a sort of
update their page it's because things
have changed and more information has
come out and you know they have varying
levels of details on the different
stances they actually start to record
some of that data you know and so if you
want to answer guys I was right your
neck guys Ernesto's conversation I'm
just watching something in my case yes
the plans for global scalability in my
mind that's one of the biggest
differences between wiki election and
all these other projects the US has an
immense amount of really good
information out there on politics part
of it is that it sort of made by and for
policy nerds
so they'll dive deep but they're the
people that kind of knew this stuff
anyway and knew where to get it and it's
only us-based
so part of it is to make it easy to
understand but then a big part of it is
making it global which means you know to
start with it's going to be can to end
the u.s. just because that's the stuff
that I know and that's it in English the
only language I speak but after that the
goals are very soon until you know start
doing it in Spanish and Hindi and a
bunch of other languages and start to
get politicians and stuff from other
areas a so that we can help out those
you know each individual country but
also because there's people who sort of
have their hands and multiple PI's
across the globe people who have moved
from politics from Canada to the US or
from the u.s. to Canada you don't get to
wipe your slate clean by doing that it
follows you forever plus I mean the
beauty of living in Canada is that we
have a lot of citizens who need it to be
in Hindi need it to be in Cantonese in
order to be able to vote effectively and
then once you figure out that language
piece they can also open up their
elections in India right
like to do that and I think also
scalability beyond global scale ability
across nations is the importance of
scalability in size right I want to be
able to use wiki elections for my coop I
want to be able to use it for my
municipality Nations eration is like
that's one of the he plans to to to to
I mean monetize isn't even the the might
work because it's not meant for profit
it's meant to pay for itself because
there's gonna like if it gets big enough
we're talking like you know we first of
all weird usage spikes like during an
election season the usage will see at
least tenfold and without a good way to
monetize that you have to be ready for
those spikes you have to have have stuff
for usage one of them is to identify the
areas or maybe you know like I talked
about doing something like this for
coops like van city well they have money
to pay for it so you you give them some
kind of a white labeled version is that
you can use this technology for your own
purpose go go nuts you just pay you know
towards the development of the
application like any other app yeah and
then for things like you know a
neighborhood co-op they might not have
to pay or or if they do you know it's a
hundred dollars a year or something
where it's it's it's minor and it's
based on sort of you know if they have
budget and what their purpose is yeah
and then being for being scalable yeah
there's the two sides of that there's
the like initially it's going to be to
be built on something like it'd be the
Amazon Cloud because that's how you make
it scalable and that's one of the few
ways to prevent the easiest thing to
disturb it which is DDoS or you know
it's a bunch of computers kind of like
take traffic but for millions of
computers dip bugs down but we do also
need a backup in case Amazon decides
that for whatever reason they don't want
us you know something this controversial
on their servers you know it's also the
beauty I hate that the tech has as much
power as they do right now but also the
tech that has power Amazon Facebook
Apple Google they're evil
and they're not evil right like like
they're like I don't think Beezus is
necessarily gonna shut you down because
he's got his billions of dollars right
like he's like and I also need to
breathe air I also need a politics and
political system like one they didn't
come from backgrounds and backgrounds of
money right so they're they're still
human they still want to keep their
slice of the pie but at the same time
they were brought like I think they get
the planet and the issues more so than
people who are like what do you mean
there's people starving and what do you
mean there's people like they're they're
human beings still and I think but I
would still plan for that you know
because you get enough people in the
right state of mind of the wrong state
of mind and yeah this is definitely
going great yeah
if tech wasn't tech like if Amazon
wasn't as public as it was they'd have
much more incentive to squash you right
to squash me to be at the same time
there's like people I see all the time
on YouTube dismantling capitalism and
they're not shutting down Richard Wolffe
they're not shutting them down because
they're giving the money right there
like right those are eyeballs we're good
go for it
even talk smack about YouTube on YouTube
like they'll say I mean those still are
love and I think a big part of it is
that yes I agree and I think of it is
you can't be a tech company and not
before innovation yeah you're like hey
we think we should have stopped
innovating in 2010 so we're just going
to fight any innovation past that point
it'd be weird for a tech company exactly
their innovation and to your to your
point because they're so public it would
be a lot harder especially if there's
kind of a sweet spot where like in the
early days before they get you know
before the election got a bunch of users
it would be possible to do it silently
but then it wouldn't be on their radar
so it's sort of once it gets big enough
to be on the radar it's too hard to shut
down that's the beauty same with the
tech cooperative yeah it's like okay
just that Amazon is so diversified that
they know one is considered competition
I would agree the only one is gonna
compete them is the globe like global
citizens and the only way that happens
more too big to fail anyway right like
Amazon's the last one we take on because
of what
people the funny thing is if like
because they're so diversified right if
they're Amazon Cloud if you know you put
this kind of a tool on there and they
decide to fight that against it all of a
sudden that becomes a pretty solid
argument to break the company up yeah
like okay you're not trying to protect
your other businesses with this business
we're not competing with the you know
with AWS yet you should have said down
on there when they're you know the best
option et cetera that would be a really
solid argument to start with the whole
you know antitrust yes that's kind of
starting anyway which yeah in there yes
absolutely okay so you're taking on
updating the prototypes for the top
three democratic people right good luck
picking the top three oh I didn't Warren
and Burnie and everything I've seen
they're the only ones pulling it in
double digits as far as I know unless
alright yeah somebody snuck tough but
even in they're probably still low and
they might be nice so interesting to see
this in like the next we're Canadian by
the way so weird by standards in the US
election we don't actually but like you
know what I mean like we don't get to
vote in it would only get to put this in
and so do it agree it's it's kind of
people outside but giving you your own
data right this is your actual data but
in the next election when running the
Republican in the Democratic race when
it's 50 people when it's but it's
crowd-sourced right so it's like does
this affect a no-name person getting to
the top right like up like wait we can
see your track record you're a trucker
it's actually amazing compared to other
people
look or does it do the opposite where
it's like people with a big name they're
gonna have boards at it like moored out
it doesn't necessarily matter in this
and at the same time right part of the
challenge in something like this is how
do you let somebody new come to the
table if you have a lifetime of politics
and let's say you're good or bad or
somewhere in the middle that least helps
people to decide but if you were you
know like somebody like Elizabeth Warren
is fairly new to the game
like she was kind of involved in the
visit the Consumer Financial Protection
Bureau or whatever it was called as far
as I know that was kind of the first
time she really entered that arena she
kind of did dabbled on the outskirts but
she doesn't really have a lethal a long
track record somebody like Bernie who's
been doing it for years as a super long
one from for somebody else that he's got
things outside of politics yes that
chicken arms as they he'll be good this
and not good it's in here sort of stuff
he values here's all the companies he
bankrupted over the years yeah and then
with it all of it I'm sure that there's
going to be things that people say about
him to end up not being true and things
that are true that no one's been saying
because it's been hard to get traction
on it and so starting to to figure that
out and to get people on both sides I'm
going to face it like oh they're willing
to say good things and bad things I'm
not used to that usually it's so skewed
one direction or or the other and I
think just that is going to be a big
shift for people all right mine I'm
gonna put out over the next I'm putting
out the doodle poll that Bentley created
for asking game B people when they're
available to pick a time and then pick a
time a time for to do it every week with
that with that group of people we
haven't yet quite figure out how to pick
the question to do that option to do it
on the weekend or evenings I mean I'm
interested in that right now no it's
well well my kids in school because it's
also kind of when he's available but
eventually that's part of it is like
having that feedback right right
other people are more interested in
evening to weekends all however it's
also global so not everyone's evening a
weekend of those things everyone else is
but to make sure that it's it as it
grows that's part of it right a part of
it it's like not everyone's fail but
what I'm available this can't require me
to host it in order for it to be
successful the YouTube channel kind of
does require me to host it the platform
won't right and so it's it's it's having
the idea cafe conversations to see what
that looks like to create the platform
and having us involved in being part of
that so I'm going to send out the doodle
poll to the game be people there was
something else I was going to do
what it was I mean host one would be
great I don't remember
besides attends my 11 a.m. do what I
suggested from yesterday are what we
agreed to yesterday during the Bentley
and I is board meeting that's live on 11
a.m. on Fridays is sitting with what it
takes to be do the scheduler part of
idea cafe and what that needs to look
like but sit with scheduler he's gonna
be much better at that than I am but I'm
the one who's like had to do the
scheduling and he's the one who has the
tech back her homes will be like and
this is possible this is like just time
zones it's hard yeah you guys need help
on that I'm very qualified Matt right
like my time at the previous companies
I've worked at that's half of what they
did was scheduling and booking and stuff
like well I think I would do uh ernesto
made a interesting comment about
political prediction trees that's one of
the nice things about and this should
actually be possible fairly early days
into a collection is when somebody is a
part of an election so you know if you
have ten thousand people who are a part
of a certain city or state or federal
election part of what they'll be able to
do is sort of crowdsource and as a
community decide on what issues they
think are important and then they go out
and look for evidence of what each
politician you know either what they've
said in the past about it or ideally
what they said about that topic in in
that election once you end up with
especially if you have enough users is
you know here's ten questions that the
community says are the most important oh
look these three no one is talking about
they haven't mentioned it in any
political rallies they haven't mentioned
it in the news no one's talking about it
but when you get enough users you're
like hey three million people have been
asking these questions the politicians
that are willing to answer them all of a
sudden that gives them a leg up busy
people who want an answer to these
questions
oh look only one of the three has
answered that all right I'll keep that
in mind
and it becomes another channel where you
have to go and you know fill out these
questions as the community agrees that
that are important
which means you can't avoid the hard
questions that people in the media don't
want to ask is maybe either it's
embarrassing or it could cause them to
lose money or it's bad for their
sponsors whatever the reason there's no
filter it's just here's what he says
they want to know who's willing to
answer that question mm-hmm no and
that's a huge important piece because
it's also like no information is bad
information if you didn't answer it if
you didn't answer my question on
pro-choice pro-life I'm gonna assume
you're the one I'm not right and so
instead of you getting to win because
you're not answering it you lose because
your honor it's like Mike Symon knows if
I'm pro-life you're pro-choice if I'm
pro-choice or pro-life unless you can
answer what you are yeah yeah it's what
I was going to say that's why I don't
know but I can hear kids thing going off
so we're gonna so you're you're taking
on updating those three I'm taking on
presenting on the scheduler and picking
a time for game B to continually have
idea cafes that whether they're on zoom
or YouTube is kind of doesn't really
matter it's more about experiencing the
idea Cafe myself to end and Bentley to
be able to figure out what those look
like for the platform so that humanity
can have a conversation and we will meet
next week we're still looking for people
if anyone wants to join who have the
tech for a tech project for purpose over
profit if and this is a medium that you
would like to participate in on video
just discussing what you're taking on
for your project and meeting at this
time and we're more than welcome also a
drill if you can send me your
information that you want people to be
able to connect to for wiki elections I
didn't put in last week's but I can
always go back and edit it and then put
it in going forward so people can see
how to contact you directly as well as
how to contact me to be part of this if
they want to sometimes the idea cafe
since this isn't actually on the idea
cafe channel because that would be weird
oh it's on the card democracy read which
is also weird all right so I'm gonna end
going live goodbye YouTube we will eat
drill and I will see you next week